Best Health Insurance Plan in ICICI Lamba
Company Today we will see in this company
which is the best plan in health insurance.
So today we
will compare two companies, one is your ICICI Lamba
Elevate Plan which is the latest and new plan
and the other is your Health Advantage Plan.
Before starting the video, let me
tell you about myself. My name is Amandeep
Singh. I have a total of five years of experience
in insurance and finance. But you will be given
all the information related to finance plus
all the information related to insurance
like health, life, car, bike, comparison of all types of
insurance, discussion
of plans, terms and conditions,
waiting periods, information on everything.
We start the video here
and move towards the video. First let's talk about
room rent. In ICICI Lamba's
Health Advantage policy, you
get a single private room if your coverage is
less than 20 lakhs. If you
take coverage of more than 20 lakhs, then there is
no capping on room rent. Similarly, if you
take the Elevate Plan of ICICI Lamba, then
your single private room will be given in it.  There is a private AC room
but you can also upgrade your room by
adding an add-on rider. If we talk about the entry age, then the
entry age for an adult is from
18 years to 65 years. The
age of a child is from 91 days to 25
days. Now let's talk about the Elevate plan in the Health Advantage policy.
Under Elevate, your age for adults is from 18
years to 125 years.
If we talk about age, then it is from 91 days to
30 years. If we talk about coverage,
coverage from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 crore is available in the Health Advantage policy.
And if we talk about IIC Lamb's
Elevate plan, then your coverage from Rs 5 lakh to
unlimited is available in it, that is
why the name of this plan is Elevate.
Talking about refill benefit, it means
that whatever coverage you take,
if you use that coverage within the same year, then
What extra
coverage does the company give you without any extra
charge? Yes, the company gives you the same coverage
in the Health Advantage policy as many times as you want for
unlimited time from the company. The
coverage you have purchased,
suppose you have purchased a policy of ₹10 lakh,
then you can take ₹10 lakh
unlimited time from the company.
You can claim for any illness within the same year. The coverage should be of ₹5 lakh
or ₹75 lakh, only then you
get extra unlimited time coverage
within the same year. Now let's talk about the
Elevate plan.
You get the same unlimited time coverage within the Elevate plan.
Here also there is no such limit of coverage
that it is available for ₹5 lakh or ₹7 lakh. It is
not like that. Here
you will get unlimited time coverage for whatever coverage you take. You
can claim for any illness
within the Elevate plan. Now let's talk about
road ambulance. Let's talk about road ambulance.
Health Advantage
Your road ambulance in the policy is your 1 per sum in
short of hospitalization
or maximum up to 100 per
hospitalization. If we talk about Elevate plan, then there is
no limit in it, you
are covered up to the sum in short. Whatever actually comes on the covered age, the
company will pay you that. Let us
talk about air ambulance coverage,
in both the policies you are covered up to the sum in
short. The
company bears your air ambulance expenses up to the maximum amount of coverage you take.
Now if we talk about the compliant
policy, then you get it once in a year,
you will get it from the first year itself, in
which your sum in short will be 0.5
or maximum up to 10 thousand. This will be on cashless
basis. Now let us talk about
Elevate plan, so in Elevate plan
you can add this as a rider, it is
not inbuilt in yours. These are pre and post
hospitalization. The pre hospitalization which is
in your health advantage policy is for
60 days and post
hospitalization.  If you take an Elevate policy for 180 days, then
your expenses up to 90 days
before the hospitalization are covered and your
expenses after 180 days are covered. This
means that if you go to the
hospital for any disease, then
whatever expenses you have incurred before that, all those
expenses can be covered for you
within 7 to 15 days. Now let's
talk about e-consultation. Consultation
means that if
you want to ask the
company's doctor as many times as you want for any disease, then you can ask that, whether it is an
Elevate policy or a Health
Advantage policy. Well, in the Elevate policy,
you can add this as a rider,
but in the Health Advantage policy,
you will get unlimited e-consultation. Your maternity
expenses are covered in both the policies. You get an e-consultation
rider. You get an
off-sum shot on maternity expenses of Rs 10 lakh. You will get a
maximum of Rs 1 lakh.  The
cover for newborn baby will be available two times.
Maternity coverage and vaccination
is also included. Up to 100% covered with two year
waiting period. Meaning, maternity will be covered
under your insurance after two years,
whether you take Elevate policy or
Health Advantage policy. Your global coverage is
covered up to ₹1 lakh or more.
Now, if we talk about Elevate policy, it is
not there in it. What
I told you earlier was for Health
Advantage policy. So, there are some additional
riders which you can add in the policy in
both the companies. In both the
plans, if we talk about the first rider of
Health Advantage, then it is
your BeFit Rider, which is an OPD rider.
Second, your Claim Protector, in which your
non-medical expenses are covered.
Third, your Sum Insured Protector,
which is your
inflation protector, in which your
coverage increases every year according to inflation.
Fourth is your maternity.  The
benefit that I have already told you is that
you can take personal accident as a rider, which means
what does the company say in case of death, the nominee will
get the money. Whatever additional personal
accidental coverage you take
along with the policy, critical illness means there is an additional
rider. You
can take a separate rider for major diseases, you
can cover critical illness within the policy, which is Rs.
20,000 per year payment. You
can choose Nursing at Home as your
additional rider within the policy. So all these riders are available
within your Health Advantage policy. Now let's
talk about the riders of Elevate policy. There are
about 18 riders in this which you
can add within the policy, in which the
first one is Durable Medical Equipment, the second one is
your Dependent Accommodation Benefit, the
third one is your Health Checkup Rider, the
fourth one is your Claim Protector, the fifth one is
Power Booster, there
is Infine's Air Ambulance, plus add-ons,
you have other additional riders as well. By the way,
everything is inbuilt within your policy,
according to me.  There is no need to add anything,
if you have to add something then definitely add that rider
which covers non-medical expenses, the
Be Fit rider which I told you about
if you take a Health Advantage policy
and if you talk about an Element policy then
you can add a rider called Claim Protector, in that
also your non-medical
expenses are covered, so you can add these two riders
in both the companies, if you
want some additional good rider which
you think can be useful, I have just
shared a quotation with you as per the family,
if you can see, here you will find the
premium of both the companies as per the family size, how much
premium is coming in which, you
can also judge your policy accordingly, you
understood the information given by me till here, if you
liked the video then you
can also follow my channel whose name is Finance
with Aman and see you
in the next video like this till then take care bye bye good bye and bye bye